hey guys my name is Alan Kuhn I live in
California and today I want to be teeth
you guys how to melbourne shuffle
first of all I would like to say that
I'm not the best at shuffling but I feel
like I'm good enough to be able to teach
the basic to you guys so without further
ado bear with me I'll make this detail
as much as I can and yeah I'll go with
it okay so the first thing I'm going to
teach you guys and what I feel like it
is the easiest thing to learn and teach
in hardstyle
is the actual shuffle or otherwise known
as the cross or the T okay so the
shuffle are known as the T is just a
simple heel-toe motion balancing on one
leg basically it's like this you guys
you have one leg up and move
Patel first and then he goes to the side
and you basically repeat that over and
over again okay to make it even more
simple for you guys when you guys are
starting to shuffle or practicing it
have your feet already in the T form
heels together one foot pointing
outwards and one foot pointing forward
and as you're doing the motion earlier
as I showed you when this when this foot
comes in this one comes up and as when
you move this back you dropped it down
to the side again so look like this
going this way too right pointing out
left pointing forward down yeah also
another thing I want to point out is
that in a lot of others shuffle tutorial
videos they make it seem like every time
you drop your foot down it has to be
right next to this foot that's
completely wrong you guys in hardstyle
when you create your own form you can
drop group you can drop your
foot anywhere
here there be anywhere watch
so remember you guys toe heel toe heel
toe okay so the second thing I'm going
to teach you guys in the second most
important basic in hardstyle shuffling
is the running man yes the thing that
makes you look like you're gliding
across the floor when you're really nine
and it's all illusion and yeah but I
want to take this time to implant this
into your head because a lot of people
think this is a serious matter and it's
not to make the running man look like
you're gliding it does not require you
having you know super light shoes the
ground the surface that you're on does
not matter it's just the technique and
the way that you do it to make it look
smooth to make it look like you're
gliding and I'm going to teach you that
right now it's not just a two-step
process it's actually a three-step
process so yeah I'm gonna take you guys
that right now pay attention alright
guys so here it is the running man I'm
going to show you guys at full speed
first and then I'm going to break it
down for you guys alright so here enjoy
pay attention watch
so as you can see I did perfectly fine
my shoes are rather poor your brown is
all ruble II and yeah I did a perfectly
fine so don't think it you have to be
wearing socks on the ground on wooden
floor to make it look like you're
sliding that's not how you do it I'm
going to show you guys right now so
watch okay you guys so part one of this
is just to take a stance one leg in
front one leg in back it doesn't matter
which foot in front I prefer my left
foot because it's just more comfortable
anyways so that's part one part two is
Jurgen you're going to jump back on your
front foot and your back foot you're
going to lift in the air so it looks
like this you guys hot back leg up see
this is part three this is really simple
but it just looked really complicated
anyways you Hawk back on the foot that
was in front and then the one that's in
hairiest drop down this so you do it
again
bump it back back foot up
Oh
more your taxes more natural again one
more time
back up drop back up drop back back up
go back I know it kind of made this look
easy
this I don't know it took me a good
while to learn this on my own and no one
you know what YouTube had this much
detail so hopefully this three-step
process instead of two helps you guys
out a great deal than it held to be in
the beginning the next thing I'm going
to show you guys are kicks and spins
just like in the shuffle have your feet
align it in the tee and as you move the
foot that's pointed outward in you lift
up and keep instead of dropping you can
kick out so it looks like this just like
in the shuffle stomps earlier instead of
stopping down to the side
stop outwards pivot your legs
creating a spin that's the best I can
teach you guys anyways I hope that this
tutorial has helped you guys you know
either a little bit or a great deal
hopefully just help you guys if you guys
have any questions don't hesitate to
send me a message or leave a question in
the comments below I'm here to help here
to give feedback and yeah don't forget
to subscribe thumbs up this video and
yeah happy happy happy shuffling my name
is Alan later